Joseph M. Kamt

Lima-Peru
Cell (+51 1) 989.163.411
joseph.kamt@gmail.com
https://www.linkedin.com/in/josephkamt

MS in Economic Research from the University of North Texas, with 10 years of proven experience implementing new corporate initiatives levered in data and technology, leading projects since early stages in design, to A/B testing, and deployment in available business technology ecosystems, with the goal of generating sustainable long-term value for customers and enterprise.

WORK HISTORY

November 2020 – Current

Cineplanet, Lima-Peru

Regional Lead Pricing and Analytics

- Lead and implemented use of new newsletter engine with imbedded machine learning capabilities for classification of favorite movies for our customer base, efforts improved open rate from historical range of 15% to over 25%.
- Took responsibility to integrate concession business unit in current pricing and analytics scheme, focusing on mix of products with highest potential, reallocating resources in operational areas, and considerably increasing unit's profitability versus pre pandemic levels. Customer's average expenditure (concessions) in 2022 increased 40% and 50% for Peru and Chile respectively compared to 2019.
- Brought in new e-commerce antifraud initiative to general management, lead implementation, and currently manage platform at corporate level. Effort reduced declined transactions from 30% historical rate to 17% within 3 months of deployment, representing an increase of over 3 million USD in annual top line revenue and a decrease in operational workload for post sales areas.
- Lead within the company projects towards centralization of customer's information, sponsored by main corporate holding. Initiative involves 25 million unique clients towards the goal to increase performance of paid social media.

July 2017 – October 2020

Cineplanet, Lima-Peru

Data Driven Growth Manager

- Integrated multiple analysis tools (SAS, R, Excel, PL-SQL, T-SQL) to deliver accurate and relevant analysis for c-suite level business decisions.
- Developed personalized box office and concession pricing model for loyalty program customers, representing 40 million PEN (12MM USD) in additional yearly revenue, about 10% in annual sales.
- Deployed multiple initiatives for data democratization within the company with the goals of digitizing outdated processes and increasing the overall productivity of relevant business areas. Estimated 15% of savings in operational salaries, representing about 5% of total company costs among others.
- Homogenized revenue management policies in Chile and Peru, aligning critical pricing criteria in Chile and increasing 5% in concession's sales per customer, along with 12% in MS growth within a month of implementation.
- Delivered customer's service scoring to operational decision makers through automated reports, auditing key processes that create value to customers in theaters. Net promoting score reached 38% from a historical 30% in over 14 months.

June 2011 – June 2016

Grupo El Comercio, Lima-Peru

Commercial Intelligence Supervisor

• Responsible for leading mid-size team of analysts (intern to senior level) and delivering information and analysis requests from business leaders within commercial business unit.

- In charge of sales incentive system, integrating team's performance analytic (key activities that lead to sales) with financial results. Kept incentive budget within goals since 2012, allowing annual increases of 5% despite 20% yearly sales growth.
- Implemented innovative methodology for tracking newspaper's subscriptions through the leverage of statistical models (logistic classification models), identifying group of customers most likely to leave. Efforts generated a 30% increase in subscriptions and a drop of 50% in customers' cancellations.
- Lead successful projects aimed at democratizing access to information, through development of data lakes and warehouses, and deployment of automated reports in Qlikview environment. Key initiatives that provided the backbone for sustainable increased productivity in sales corporate suite.

SKILLS

- Machine Learning Modeling Logistical Regressions / Neural Networks / Supervised and Unsupervised Classification Methods / Time Series
- Python / R / Transact SQL / PL SQL / SAS Programming
- Microsoft Office Suite Tools
- Workflows in Jupyter Notebooks and GCP environments

- Commercial Planning
- Revenue Management and Pricing
- BI & TI Project Management
- Team Building
- Problem Solving
- Effective Communication
- English and Spanish communication (native)

EDUCATION

2014 - 2016	UNIVERSIDAD DEL PACIFICO
	 Master of Business Administration (MBA)
2008 - 2010	UNIVERSITY OF NORTH TEXAS
	 Master of Science in Economic Research (MSER)
2004 - 2007	UNIVERSITY OF NORTH TEXAS
	 Bachelor of Arts in Economics (Cum Laude - quinto superior)
	 Bachelor of Arts in International Studies (Cum Laude - quinto superior)

ADDITIONAL COURSEWORK

- IBM Data Science IBM/EdX (on going)
- Preparing for Google Cloud Certification: Cloud Data Engineer – Google Cloud/Coursera (May 2020)
- Python Programmer DataCamp (Mar 2020)
- Data Engineering, Big Data, and Machine Learning on GCP – Google Cloud/Coursera (Nov 2019)
- Data Science: Foundations Using R Johns Hopkins University/Coursera (Oct 2019)

- Machine Learning Stanford University/Coursera (Jun 2019)
- Applied Analytics Using SAS Enterprise Miner SAS (Sep 2018)
- PL/SQL Oracle 12c Cibertec (May 2017)
- Design Thinking Lab Universidad del Pacifico (Mar 2016)
- Database Modeling Cibertec (Oct 2015)